Register of the Karl August Wittfogel papers, 1728-1992
Hoover Institution Archives
- MICROFILM REELS, 1832-1938
  - Communist International (Comintern) (Reels 3-5)
  - Far East (Reel 6)
  - Hegel, G. W. (Reel 7)
  - Die Internationale. Articles by KAW, 1927-1928 (Reel 8)
    - "Wang Tsching Wei: Der politische Fuhrer der Kantonregierung," 1927
    - "Der proletarische Kampf gegen den weissen Terror in China," 1927
    - "Renegaten der chinesischen Revolution," 1927-1928
  - International News Correspondence, 1922 Oct. 1-1924 Dec. 31 (Reel 9)
  - Lenin, Vladimir Illich (Reel 10)
  - Mao, Tse-tung (Reel 11)
  - Marx, Karl (Reels 12-14)
  - Most, Johann (Reel 15)
- PHONORECORDS, n.d.
  - "Music of the Sioux and Navajo," n.d. (recorded by Professor Willard Rhodes) (Oversize Record cabinet)
  - "Native Brazilian Music," n.d. (recorded by Leopold Stokowski)
- VIDEOTAPE CASSETTE, 1982 March 23.
  - Recording of lecture by Wittfogel on Oriental Despotism given in Germany (Oversize Tape cabinet)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS, 1919-1954
  - Placard announcing a series of six speeches on Chinese poetry, wisdom, and belief, Berlin, Germany, 1919 June-August (Map-case Map case)
  - Placard announcing a series of three speeches entitled "A History of Chinese Communism: Facts and Lessons," University of Notre Dame, South Bend, Illinois, 1954 October 24-25
  - Research materials for the Chinese History Project, n.d.
  - Lithographs
- PHOTOGRAPHS., 1704 prints, 4482 negatives, 24 albums, 19 slides / 61 envelopes, 6 album boxes, 1 slide box. (Box 66033 - 10.A-V, 57.05, slide cabinet)
  - 24 photo albums depicting people and places throughout Europe, Mexico and Peru., 1948-1970's (Folder fA-fX)
    Includes prints of Karl Wittfogel at his work.
  - 150 prints of Karl Wittfogel in his youth., undated (Folder Y-AA)
  - 23 prints of Karl Wittfogel's family., undated (Folder AB)
    Includes prints of his mother and father.
  - 51 prints., undated (Folder AC)
    Includes 47 prints of Karl Wittfogel's mother and 4 prints of family graves.
  - 54 prints, includes 39 prints of Olga Joffe (Wittfogel's second wife) and 15 prints of Wittfogel and Joffe., undated (Folder AD)
  - 43 prints., undated (Folder AE)
    Includes 22 prints of Esther Goldfrank (Wittfogel's third wife) and 21 prints of Wittfogel and Goldfrank.
  - 190 prints of Karl Wittfogel., undated (Folder AF-AJ)
    Includes 13 prints of Wittfogel's personal effects and 53 prints of Wittfogel's years at the International Institut fur Sozialforschung an der Universitat Frankfurt am Main.
  - 23 prints of identified family members., undated (Folder AK)
  - 62 prints of identified friends and acquaintances., undated (Folder AL)
  - 48 prints of identified figures., undated (Folder AM)
  - 234 prints of unidentified people., undated (Folder AN-AP)
  - 188 prints of unidentified and identified scenes., undated (Folder AQ-AS)
    Includes 11 prints of Woltersdorf in envelope AS.
  - 204 prints of Wittfogel's summer residence, Cornwall, N.Y., undated (Folder AT-AV)
    Includes 3 prints of Wittfogel.
  - 112 prints of Wittfogel's years in Seattle, WA., 1959-1963 (Folder AW)
    Includes 13 prints of Wittfogel.
  - 80 prints of Spain, great Britain and Europe (circa 1957), undated (Folder AX-AY)
  - 23 prints of Isfahan, Iran., undated (Folder AZ)
    Includes negatives.
  - 52 prints and 39 postcards of Japan, circa 1957 (Folder BA)
  - 45 prints of China., undated (Folder BB-BC)
    Includes 19 prints of Wittfogel, and postcards sent by Yoshitaro Hirano with an image of the Kiso River, and from Wittfogel's mother, Johanne Wittfogel, from Lineburg, Germany.
  - 67 prints of Australia., undated (Folder BD)
    Includes 1 print of Wittfogel.
  - 4 prints of American Indians., undated (Folder BE)
    Negatives included.
  - 28 miscellaneous postcards., undated (Folder BF)
  - 12 prints of miscellaneous art work., undated (Folder BG)
  - 1 unidentified print of a school class photo., undated (Folder BH)
  - 2 prints of the 1927 Central Executive Committee of the Kuomintang, 1st Session., undated (Folder BI)
  - 16 negatives of Karl and Esther Wittfogel., undated (Folder BJ)
  - 167 negatives of identified and unidentified people and scenes., undated (Folder BK)
    Includes 6 negatives of Esther Wittfogel and 7 negatives of Karl Wittfogel.
  - 40 negatives of Bertram and Ella Wolfe at Cornwall, NY., undated (Folder BL)
  - 1428 negatives of Wittfogel's summer residence, Cornwall, NY., undated (Folder BM-BR)
    Includes some negatives of the University of Washington.
  - 959 negatives from various states in the United States., undated (Folder BS-BV)
    Includes negatives of Wittfogel's residences in New York and Seattle.
  - 324 negatives of Hawaii, Japan and Hong Kong., undated (Folder BW)
  - 624 negatives of Europe., undated (Folder BX-BZ)
    Includes the Netherlands, Switzerland, Germany, Spain and Great Britain.
  - 548 negatives of South America., circa 1955 (Folder CA-CB)
    Includes negatives of Peru and Mexico.
  - 290 negatives of identified and unidentified scenes., undated (Folder CC)
  - 14 miscellaneous negatives., undated (Folder CD)
  - 72 negatives of London and Interlocken., undated (Folder CE)
  - 3 miscellaneous prints., undated (Folder CF)
    Includes 1 print of Zbigniew Brzezinski and Karl Wittfogel.
  - 45 prints of scenes from the May 1968 student protest in France., undated (Folder CG)
  - 14 glass slides of China and 5 miscellaneous slides., undated (Folder Slide cabinet)